# **Robyn Stokes**

Senior Front-End Developer, Graphic Designer, and Team Leader with over 15 years of experience combining both my interactive development and design knowledge to deliver digital solutions for both small and large businesses.

US/International (630) 418-4017 robynlynnestokes@gmail.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Critical Mass, Chicago, IL — Technology Lead

SEP 2021 - PRESENT

- Collaborating with multiple high-profile clients on strategic projects
- Currently hold active CAC card with t3 clearance while maintaining a government website.
- Quickly advanced to Tech Lead in just over a year, demonstrating exceptional leadership, technical
  expertise, and a knack for bridging gaps to ensure project success.
- Co-Lead large team of developers using AEM, storybook, tailwind, react, node and gitlab all within
  a government cloud environment
- Initiated the implementation of AI developer tools like copilot and chatGPT
- Implemented and lead Women in Tech group within Critical Mass company
- Given seat on WIT-h (https://women-in-tech.org/) global mentoring program
- Involved in tech staffing and recruitment initiatives as hiring manager
- Lead high-impact projects from conception to delivery, managing planning, execution, and cross-team coordination to ensure timely, high-quality solutions aligned with business goals.
- Leverage deep knowledge of software development to design and implement robust, scalable, and
  efficient solutions.
- Stay current on emerging technologies to drive innovation, mentor developers, and foster a culture of growth and knowledge sharing.
- Streamline workflows and introduced best practices for code reviews, testing, and deployment.

# Czarnowski, Chicago, IL — Senior Front-End Developer

NOV 2016 - SEP 2021

- Created several dynamic internal applications and websites for Czarnowski as well as for their clients such as Coke, Porsche, GM, Abbvie, Toyota, and many more leveraging Thymeleaf, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Wordpress, Jquery and JavaScript (working with Java/Spring backend).
- Conceptualized, designed and created custom site designs, logos, icons, banners, templates, etc.
- Worked with project managers and team leads to meet the business needs as required.
- Worked with a separate team of 3D artists, designers and project managers to create 360° and other unique interactive virtual experiences for clients such as Coke, Abbvie, Seagen, TAE and more.

# Web Works, Chicago, IL — Senior Front-End Developer/OM

MARCH 2014 - AUGUST 2016

- Implemented a proper coding, testing and development environment including responsive, mobile friendly development processes, team scrum, and mobile testing
- Designed and developed dozens of new responsive and mobile friendly websites.
- Implemented social media marketing for Web Works utilizing several online resources including Twitter, Facebook, Pinterest and more.
- Conceptualized, designed and customized internal programs and apps which helped maintain, track & provide a more efficient internal working environment for the Web Works team and our clients; some of these apps included a customized Jira environment which directly imported our custom client portal inquiries and site update requests into a Jira Service Desk environment.
- As operations manager I oversaw and managed all Development, Billing, Sales, Marketing, Consulting, Client Support, New Business, Research, Training along with managing 4 shared hosting servers, 75+ private hosting servers, 1500+ hosted emails, 800+ websites, 30+ Wordpress Sites, 50+ databases.
- Generated income from multiple lost revenue sources including additional products & services not being charged for. Also eliminated 100's of unused services, and products saving the company thousands in yearly costs.

#### **CLIENTS**

ARMY, Delta Faucet, Coke, Porsche, GM, Abbvie, Toyota, Anixter, McDonald's, Bridgestone, Craftsman, Sears, Kmart, Whirlpool, Gladiator GarageWorks, Amana, Columbia College, Roosevelt College, Depaul University, Marriott, Bear Necessities Cancer Foundation, American Heart Association, The Chicago Collection, Kenmore, TAE Life Sciences, Voximetry, Lilly, Grainger, and more...

#### **LEADERSHIP QUALITIES**

Technical Leadership, Project
Management, Cross-functional Team
Collaboration, Agile Methodologies,
Problem Solving, Mentorship,
Training and Coaching, Stakeholder
Management, Bridging Gaps,
Streamline Processes, Delivering and
Innovation

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery,
Bootstrap, Thymeleaf, PHP,
WordPress, AEM, Marzipano,
Monetate, Adobe Target, Adobe
Launch, Deque, Ace Components,
Mobile First/ Responsive Website
Design & Development, Eclipse,
PHPStorm, IntelliJ, VS Code, Microsoft
Suite, Adobe Suite of Professional
Products, Figma, Atlassian, UX,
Accessibility, Photography,
Professional photo editing, Graphic
Design and E-Commerce experience

# The UX Factory, Chicago, IL — Senior Front-End Developer

MARCH 2013 - AUGUST 2016

- Helped manage several large client websites and private servers while managing Web Works, their sister company. Clients included: Anixter, McDonald's, Bridgestone, PharmaStart and more.
- Setup and maintained private Wordpress hosting environment
- Designed and developed several new client websites
- Collaborated with development team (and other disciplinary tracks) to implement pixel-perfect designs for an order entry application
- Leveraged IceFaces, JQUERY, HTML, CSS and JSF to craft the web solution
- Implemented front-end code based on PSD designs and propagated design through the site
- Participated in the management of tasks and resources for the front-end development team as well as ensured UX vision was extended and consistently implemented throughout the application
- Presented solutions and clickable prototypes to stakeholders, management and project teams

## **Sears/Kmart**, Hoffman Estates, IL — Front-End Developer

MARCH 2013 - AUGUST 2016

- Worked with a team of developers to create, launch and maintain the Craftsman Club beta site using Bootstrap and AngularJS.
- Transformed complex, high quality PSD designs into multi-browser compliant code
- Implemented standards compliant CSS/HTML to create pixel-perfect web pages.
- Created and maintained project management documents helping organize our team and tasks to meet deadlines efficiently

## **ARS Interactive, Palatine, IL** — Front-End Developer

MARCH 2013 - AUGUST 2016

- Worked directly with designers and project managers to transform complex, high quality PSD
  design into hand coded standards compliant CSS/HTML to create pixel-perfect web pages for
  clients including: Craftsman, Kenmore, Whirlpool, Kmart, Sears, Gladiator GarageWorks and more
- Developed multiple promotional HTML-based emails for and ensured compatibility across various email clients and browsers.
- Advocated a web-standards approach to increase search engine optimization and accessibility as well as pushed adoption of mobile support.
- Mobile Device Development for Craftsman, Kenmore, Whirlpool and Sears.
- Designed and developed a number of websites using custom HTML, CSS built on top of the WordPress blog engine.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Columbia College Chicago, Chicago, IL — Bachelor of Arts

**GRADUATED WITH HONORS CLASS OF 2005** 

Major: Interactive Multimedia / Minors: Photography and Journalism

#### **SECURITY CLEARANCE**

## **Security Level** — *CAC* with T3 Clearance – level 1 in progress

March 2023-Current

#### **MOST RECENT PROJECTS**

#### **VOLUNTEERING**

**Burton Chill Program:** Snowboard Instructor & Director in Algonquin, IL

**Raging Buffalo:** Snowsports School Director in Algonquin, IL

American Heart Association: Photographer in Chicago, IL

**Bear Necessities:** Photographer in Chicago, IL

Maywood Fine Arts Center: Art Teacher in Maywood, IL

#### **AWARDS**

Featured In: Sun Times, Pioneer Press, West Suburban Journal, The Reader, The Chronicle, Chicago Magazine, Chicago Architecture, The Chicago Collection, Best Doctors & Hospitals, Chicago Health Magazine & Midwest Shred Magazine

Presented social media workshops sponsored and promoted by: Columbia College Chicago, DePaul, Bartlett Hills Country Club, Prism Photo, Marriott, Invitations by Design, Systemtek Web Consultants and more.

#### **INTERESTS**

Snowboarding, mountain biking, photography, gaming, cooking, gardening, writing & volunteering

## **REFERENCES**

Available upon request.

### **GOARMY.com** — Out with the Old in with the New

Starting as a Senior Front-End Developer, I quickly advanced to Tech Lead within 14 months, overcoming challenges of a limited budget and outdated AEM environment. I expanded the development team, led the integration of AI technologies to boost efficiency, and overhauled workflows for improved productivity. I directed the reskinning and relaunch of goarmy.com, upgrading to the latest AEM version and implementing a modern build process. Serving as a key liaison between teams and stakeholders, I ensured clear communication, managed tight deadlines, and consistently delivered high-quality projects on time.

## **Client Portal** — Customizable Client Inventory Management Tool

Collaborating with a team of five backend Java developers, we leveraged Thymeleaf, Java, Spring, and a dynamic API to build a customizable client inventory portal. This platform allowed clients to efficiently manage their inventory, create wishlists, and schedule events, all while aligning the site with their unique company branding. The portal also empowered project managers to seamlessly tailor the user interface to match each client's specific needs, resulting in a versatile tool that enhanced both client satisfaction and operational efficiency.

## **Coke/Sonic** — Online Interactive Store Experience

Worked with a cross-functional team of designers, backend Java developers, and project managers to craft an immersive digital experience for Sonic franchises. This interactive platform allowed users to virtually explore a Sonic Restaurant, visualizing Coke products within the environment. We also developed the "Mix it Up" game, engaging users with a dynamic experience where they could win cash prizes, blending entertainment with brand integration..

#### **CLOSING STATEMENT**

I am a passionate and forward-thinking tech leader dedicated to driving innovation, empowering teams, and delivering impactful solutions. With a strong foundation in both technical expertise and strategic collaboration, I thrive in dynamic environments where creativity, mentorship, and problem-solving meet. As I continue to grow in my career, I am eager to leverage my skills to inspire meaningful change and foster the next generation of technology professionals.